<?xml version="1.0"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Robin Nilsson</title>
    <link href="https://robin.se/blog" />
    <link type="application/atom+xml" rel="self" href="https://robin.se/blog/feed.atom" />
    <updated>2021-11-01T09:54:20+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://robin.se/blog/feed.atom</id>
    <author>
        <name>Robin Nilsson</name>
    </author>
                <entry>
    <id>https://robin.se/blog/my-digital-nomad-gear-list</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://robin.se/blog/my-digital-nomad-gear-list" />
    <title>My digital nomad packing list</title>
    <published>2021-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2021-06-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Robin Nilsson</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">The new normal is boosting the number of remote workers, and it is here to stay! 🥳
If you are a traveling remote worker, you&#039;ll want to consider using one carry-on size backpack for all of your stuff. They are usually up to around 40L depending on the......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>The new normal is boosting the number of remote workers, and it is here to stay! 🥳<br />
If you are a traveling remote worker, you'll want to consider using one carry-on size backpack for all of your stuff. They are usually up to around 40L depending on the airline.</p>

<h3>Now, why would you want only one small-ish bag?</h3>

<ul>
<li>It's cheap! The price of airplane tickets are considerably less without checked luggage.</li>
<li>Never worry about lost checked bags. You have everything above your head.</li>
<li>Saves time in the airport. Go straight to security and skip the baggage claim!</li>
<li>It will force you to only bring things that you will actually use.</li>
<li>Easy and cheap transport. No problem getting on that $2 scooter.</li>
<li>You won't look like the typical tourist.</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h2>My packing list</h2>

<h3>Tech</h3>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Macbook Air M1</strong><br />
This is an absolute beast. Light and cheap with the performance of a last gen Macbook Pro 15" 🤤</p></li>
<li><p><strong>HyperJuice 100W GaN charger</strong><br />
Another beast. Charges all my devices without a sweat.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>DJI Mini 2</strong><br />
I only travel with the actual drone and controller to save space.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>GoPro Hero 8 Black</strong><br />
With the magnetic swivel clip and a strap.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Anker USB-C to Lightning</strong><br />
Been using this for almost two years now. Still looks brand new!</p></li>
<li><p><strong>JBL GO 3</strong><br />
Small speaker with good sound and <em>USB-C port</em> for charging.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>AirPods Pro</strong><br />
I previously used the infamous Bose QC 35 II and the AirPods has won me over. It is unbelievable how they managed to make the noise-cancelling so good. Saves space in my bag, too!</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Anker USB-C memory card reader</strong><br />
Tiny and fast. Takes both SD and micro SD cards.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Mophie Powerstation 5000mAh</strong><br />
Compact and sleek design. Power input and output via USB-C, with one USB-A port.</p></li>
</ul>

<h3>Clothing</h3>

<p>Merino wool is the way to go. It is breathable, keeps you warm when it's cold, cools you down when it's hot, and it is odour resistant! 
You can easily wear the same shirt for a week straight. Just let it aerate after each wear. 
You can read more about merino wool on <a href="https://packhacker.com/guide/merino-wool-travel-clothing/">Packhacker</a>.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Lululemon ABC Slim pants</strong></li>
<li><strong>Helly Hansen Loke – packable wind breaker</strong></li>
<li><strong>2x Wool And Prince Crew T-shirt</strong></li>
<li><strong>2x Icebreaker Cool-Lite Crew T-shirt</strong></li>
<li><strong>2x Regular T-shirts. Just to mix it up</strong></li>
<li><strong>2x Icebreaker Anatomica boxers</strong></li>
<li><strong>2x Swim shorts</strong></li>
<li><strong>Darn Tough No-Show socks</strong></li>
<li><strong>Billabong flip-flops</strong></li>
<li><strong>Skechers GoWalk 5</strong></li>
</ul>

<h3>Personal care</h3>

<ul>
<li><strong>Dr Bronner`s soap</strong><br />
All purpose vegan soap! Can be used on your entire body, washing clothes or even brushing your teeth!</li>
<li><strong>Gillette Styler</strong><br />
Small, cheap and runs on one AA battery.</li>
<li>**Nuud*<br />
This is a tiny, vegan, super concentrated deodorant that you only have to apply every 3-7 days. If you get another brand, make sure it's not an antiperspirant since it will wear out the merino wool faster.</li>
<li><strong>Bamboo toothbrush</strong></li>
<li><strong>Mini toothpaste</strong></li>
</ul>

<h3>Miscellaneous</h3>

<ul>
<li><strong>Ticket to the moon(TTTM) hammock with the Lightest straps</strong><br />
This takes up some space, but I couldn't leave without this bad boy. Nothing beats chilling in the hammock after a long day of exploring. I am thinking about getting the lightest TTTM hammock, but I will have to try it out first.</li>
<li><strong>Eagle creek compression packing cubes</strong><br />
A necessity for all travelers. Organize and compress your clothes!</li>
<li><strong>Wallet</strong><br />
I just use a hairband to hold a debit card and cash together 🤷‍♂️</li>
</ul>

<h3>Backpack</h3>

<p>I currently use the <strong>DB Carry All 40L</strong>. It is certainly not the best backpack – lacking a laptop compartment, other smart stuff and comfort, but I like the look of it. Next upgrade(or downgrade) will probably be the expandable Tortuga Setout Divide 26L-34L.</p>

<h3>Conclusion</h3>

<p>Do your own thing. This is just what works for me. You will most likely have different needs.</p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://robin.se/blog/macos-tips-boost-productivity</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://robin.se/blog/macos-tips-boost-productivity" />
    <title>5 MacOS tips to boost your productivity</title>
    <published>2019-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Robin Nilsson</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">Reducing the time doing stuff you do regularly is necessary if you want to get shit done. It&#039;s called being productive. Start small and find shortcuts to the thing you do the most.

Next level is automating predictive tasks. But that&#039;s for another post.......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>Reducing the time doing stuff you do regularly is necessary if you want to get shit done. It's called being productive. Start small and find shortcuts to the thing you do the most.</p>

<p>Next level is automating predictive tasks. But that's for another post.</p>

<h2>1. Leveraging the spotlight search</h2>

<p>You probably know that you can use something called Spotlight search to find applications and files. I use it <em>all</em> the time.
But did you know it can do a lot more? It can tell you the weather, do math, currency conversions, unit conversions, find contacts, etc. 🕵🏻‍♂️</p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/robin-se/image/upload/v1567021663/spotlight-currency-conversion_vkh79w.png" alt="Currency conversion in Spotlight" /></p>

<h2>2. Paste and match style</h2>

<p>Sometimes when you paste text, it does not match the style of the rest of the content. To fix this, press <code>CMD + SHIFT + OPTION + V</code> instead of the regular <code>CMD + V</code>. This is universal and it should work in most applications.</p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/robin-se/image/upload/v1567021596/pasted-text_txzsdb.png" alt="Paste and match style" /></p>

<h2>3. Save screenshots in clipboard</h2>

<p>I use this one all the time. Instead of pressing <code>CMD + SHIFT + 4</code> to take a screenshot. Use <code>CMD + SHIFT + OPTION + 4</code>. This will save it to your clipboard so you can paste it in most applications.
I've even changed my shortcut bindings to the regular <code>CMD + SHIFT + 4</code> for this one because I use it frequently.</p>

<h2>4. Hide the dock</h2>

<p>You know that bar at the bottom with all of your apps? It takes up screen- and workspace. Press <code>CMD + OPTION + D</code> to toggle it.</p>

<p>This is especially useful if you don't have a large external monitor.</p>

<h2>5. Switching between windows</h2>

<p>Having multiple browser and code editor windows open has to be something most developers have in common. I think that most people reach for the dock and right-click to application to change window. However – I think there is a much better way to do it. I use two different solutions.</p>

<h3>Hot corners</h3>

<p>This is the one I use most. It allows me to flick my cursor to the top left corner(pick any corner you want) to reveal all open windows of the application currently in focus. Great when you have a lot of open windows.</p>

<p>You can find the preference page by using Spotlight! 😎
<img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/robin-se/image/upload/v1567022183/Screen_Shot_2019-08-28_at_21.56.08_xjwzdk.png" alt="" /></p>

<h3>The backtick shortcut?</h3>

<p><code>CMD + SHIFT + `</code></p>

<p>Don't know what to call this one, but it's super useful when I need to switch between 2-3 open windows. More than 3 and cycling between the windows gets annoying.</p>

<hr />

<h2>Bonus</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://imageoptim.com/mac">Imageoptim</a> is a breeze for compressing images 🍃</li>
<li><a href="https://www.spectacleapp.com">Spectacle</a> lets you arrange your windows like a grid + more</li>
<li><a href="https://insomnia.rest">Insomnia</a> is a better version of Postman</li>
<li>Insert Emojis with <code>CMD + CONTROL + SPACE BAR</code></li>
<li>You can find a lot more shortcuts at <a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201236">Apple Support</a></li>
</ul>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://robin.se/blog/special-characters-eloquent-sluggable</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://robin.se/blog/special-characters-eloquent-sluggable" />
    <title>ÅÄÖ characters in Eloquent Sluggable</title>
    <published>2019-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Robin Nilsson</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">In Sweden, we have three letters that might look weird to you: Å, Ä and Ö, so this post is mainly for Swedes.

Usually, you don&#039;t want to use these characters in, for example, slugs. Therefore most slug generators will translate Å to A, Ä to A and......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>In Sweden, we have three letters that might look weird to you: Å, Ä and Ö, so this post is mainly for Swedes.</p>

<p>Usually, you don't want to use these characters in, for example, slugs. Therefore most slug generators will translate Å to A, Ä to A and Ö to O.</p>

<p>I use the package <a href="https://github.com/cviebrock/eloquent-sluggable">eloquent-sluggable</a> in my Laravel projects, which I love! However, this package does not generate slugs using the method above. Ö translates to OE, which is wrong.</p>

<h2>1. Publish config</h2>

<pre><code class="language-bash">php artisan vendor:publish --provider="Cviebrock\EloquentSluggable\ServiceProvider"
</code></pre>

<h2>2. Set slug helper as method</h2>

<p>You'll find <code>sluggable.php</code> in your config directory.</p>

<pre><code>[
    ...
    'method' =&gt; function($string) {
        return Str::slug($string);
    },
    ...
]
</code></pre>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://robin.se/blog/awesome-tool-to-find-domain-names</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://robin.se/blog/awesome-tool-to-find-domain-names" />
    <title>An awesome tool to find domain names</title>
    <published>2019-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Robin Nilsson</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">Domain names are in high demand and it&#039;s a huge business buying and selling them. To find your own domain name can be super difficult if not impossible.

I recently discovered that you can use a more advanced search at Namecheap. They call it Beast mode......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>Domain names are in high demand and it's a huge business buying and selling them. To find your own domain name can be super difficult if not impossible.</p>

<p>I recently discovered that you can use a more advanced search at Namecheap. They call it Beast mode and it's pretty cool!</p>

<p>https://www.namecheap.com/domains/registration/results.aspx?type=beast</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/namecheap-beast-mode.png" alt="Beast Mode" /></p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://robin.se/blog/custom-404-page-laravel-forge</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://robin.se/blog/custom-404-page-laravel-forge" />
    <title>Custom 404 page for Jigsaw in Laravel Forge</title>
    <published>2019-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Robin Nilsson</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">This site is built with Tightens Jigsaw and runs on Laravel Forge. The 404 page did not work out of the box.

Tighten tells you to add &lt;code&gt;error_page 404 /404;&lt;/code&gt; to the Nginx config. That is true. But it does not work in Forge.
The solution is to......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>This site is built with Tightens Jigsaw and runs on Laravel Forge. The 404 page did not work out of the box.</p>

<p><a href="https://jigsaw.tighten.co/docs/custom-404-page/">Tighten tells you</a> to add <code>error_page 404 /404;</code> to the Nginx config. That is true. But it does not work in Forge.<br />
The solution is to add one more line. <code>fastcgi_intercept_errors on;</code></p>

<pre><code class="language-nginx"># FORGE CONFIG (DO NOT REMOVE!)
include forge-conf/robin.se/server/*;

fastcgi_intercept_errors on;

location / {
    try_files $uri $uri/ /index.php?$query_string;
}

location = /favicon.ico { access_log off; log_not_found off; }
location = /robots.txt  { access_log off; log_not_found off; }

access_log off;
error_log  /var/log/nginx/robin.se-error.log error;

error_page 404 /404;

location ~ \.php$ {
    fastcgi_split_path_info ^(.+\.php)(/.+)$;
    fastcgi_pass unix:/var/run/php/php7.2-fpm.sock;
    fastcgi_index index.php;
    include fastcgi_params;
}
</code></pre>

<p>Don't forget to restart Nginx!</p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://robin.se/blog/cloudflare-actually-slows-your-website-down</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://robin.se/blog/cloudflare-actually-slows-your-website-down" />
    <title>Cloudflare actually slows your website down</title>
    <published>2019-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2019-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Robin Nilsson</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">So I&#039;ve almost always used Cloudflare for my personal websites. Recently I started asking my self why? Is it better than just a DNS?

I don&#039;t need the security, DDOS protection, caching, auto minify or Rocket Loader. And I don&#039;t care that you can see my......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>So I've almost always used Cloudflare for my personal websites. Recently I started asking my self why? Is it better than just a DNS?</p>

<p>I don't need the security, DDOS protection, caching, auto minify or Rocket Loader. And I don't care that you can see my servers IP address.</p>

<h2>Time to speed test</h2>

<p>Pingdom Tools and Gtmetrix are probably the best free speed test services out there.</p>

<p>Not sure why Pingdom's screenshot is not working. Nevertheless – I was chocked by the speed difference.</p>

<h3>With Cloudflare</h3>

<p><img src="/assets/images/cloudflare-speed/pingdom-with-cloudflare.png" alt="Pingdom Tools speed test with Cloudflare" />
<img src="/assets/images/cloudflare-speed/gtmetrix-with-cloudflare.png" alt="GTmetrix speed test with Cloudflare" /></p>

<h3>Without Cloudflare</h3>

<p><img src="/assets/images/cloudflare-speed/pingdom-without-cloudflare.png" alt="Pingdom Tools speed test without Cloudflare" />
<strong>31.7% faster</strong></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/cloudflare-speed/gtmetrix-without-cloudflare.png" alt="GTmetrix speed test without Cloudflare" />
<strong>47.6% faster!</strong></p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>You probably don't need Cloudflare. Just use a solid DNS provider along with a CDN, and you'll be golden.</p>

<p>This site is served with static HTML files. With a more complex and dynamic website you might get different results. Better or worse? Do you know? <a href="&#x6d;&#x61;&#105;&#108;&#x74;&#x6f;&#58;&#104;e&#x6a;&#x40;&#114;&#111;&#x62;&#x69;&#110;&#46;s&#x65;">Send me an email!</a></p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://robin.se/blog/custom-404-page</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://robin.se/blog/custom-404-page" />
    <title>Custom 404 Pages</title>
    <published>2018-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Robin Nilsson</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">This starter template includes a custom 404 Not Found error page, located at &lt;code&gt;/source/404.blade.php&lt;/code&gt;. To preview the 404 page, you can visit &lt;code&gt;/404&lt;/code&gt; in your browser.





Depending on where your site is hosted, you may need to......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>This starter template includes a custom <strong>404 Not Found</strong> error page, located at <code>/source/404.blade.php</code>. <a href="/404">To preview the 404 page</a>, you can visit <code>/404</code> in your browser.</p>

<pre><code class="language-html">&lt;!-- source/404.blade.php --&gt;

@extends('_layouts.master')

@section('body')
    &lt;div class="flex flex-col items-center text-gray-700 mt-32"&gt;
        &lt;h1 class="text-6xl font-light leading-none mb-2"&gt;404&lt;/h1&gt;

        &lt;h2 class="text-3xl"&gt;Page not found.&lt;/h2&gt;

        &lt;hr class="block w-full max-w-sm mx-auto border my-8"&gt;

        &lt;p class="text-xl"&gt;
            Need to update this page? See the &lt;a title="404 Page Documentation" href="https://jigsaw.tighten.co/docs/custom-404-page/"&gt;Jigsaw documentation&lt;/a&gt;.
        &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
@endsection
</code></pre>

<hr />

<p>Depending on where your site is hosted, you may need to configure your server to use the custom 404 page. For more details, visit the <a href="https://jigsaw.tighten.co/docs/custom-404-page/">Jigsaw documentation about configuring a custom 404 page</a>.</p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://robin.se/blog/about-my-domain-name</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://robin.se/blog/about-my-domain-name" />
    <title>About my domain name</title>
    <published>2018-09-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-09-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Robin Nilsson</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">I get a lot of reactions from people about my domain name. Everyone from the guy at the bank to fellow developers.

No, I wasn&#039;t fast enough to register it. I was probably like ten when it was registered for the first time 😄.
I bought the domain name......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>I get a lot of reactions from people about my domain name. Everyone from the guy at the bank to fellow developers.</p>

<p><strong>No, I wasn't fast enough to register it.</strong> I was probably like ten when it was registered for the first time 😄.
I bought the domain name in early 2017 from a company that specialises in trading domains.</p>

<p>It was 8 000 SEK which is about 775 EUR or 910 USD. My friends thought I was a fool for hurling that amount on a domain name. Well, jokes on them. I've already received offers for 4-5 times of what I payed. Money well spent!</p>

<p>But it's certainly not all about the money. That's not why I bought it. A web-guy should have a good domain name, right? Wouldn't you buy a premium car if you were a cab driver?</p>

<p>There is however a whole business buying and selling domain names. And with the web still growing in a rapid pace, that's not going anywhere.</p>

<p>This domain will probably be in my possession until I retire. By then it should probably be worth enough to do something awesome 👴</p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://robin.se/blog/pretty-php-dumps-using-highlight_string</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://robin.se/blog/pretty-php-dumps-using-highlight_string" />
    <title>Pretty PHP dumps using highlight_string()</title>
    <published>2018-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Robin Nilsson</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">This is a nice little trick if you’re sick of the almost impossible to read var_dump.





And it should come out something like this. Nice, eh?...</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>This is a nice little trick if you’re sick of the almost impossible to read var_dump.</p>

<pre><code class="language-php">function dump($data) {
    highlight_string("&lt;?php\n" . var_export($data, true) . "\n");
}
</code></pre>

<pre><code class="language-php">&lt;?php dump(['foo' =&gt; 'bar', 'baz' =&gt; 'foobar', 'status' =&gt; true]); ?&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>And it should come out something like this. Nice, eh?</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/php-highlighted.png" alt="Highlighted PHP code" /></p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://robin.se/blog/fetch-media-from-production-to-local-environment</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://robin.se/blog/fetch-media-from-production-to-local-environment" />
    <title>Fetch media from production to local environment</title>
    <published>2018-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Robin Nilsson</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">Why download images and other heavy resources to your local computer, when you have them available to the public? This does not only save space on your local hard drive. It saves a lot of time syncing resources from production to your local environment.......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>Why download images and other heavy resources to your local computer, when you have them available to the public? This does not only save space on your local hard drive. It saves a lot of time syncing resources from production to your local environment.</p>

<p>This snippet first checks if the resource is present in your local space. Its not? 
Then fetch it from the specified production URL. So awesome!</p>

<p>I'm pretty sure this will work for setups that's not using Valet, but I have not tested it outside of Valet.</p>

<p>Your Nginx config file is found in <code>.config/valet/Nginx/yourdomain.test</code> or the old path <code>.valet/Nginx/yourdomain.test</code>.</p>

<p>This file will not be present without running <code>valet secure</code> in your site root. Go ahead and run that if you can't see your domain. If you, like me, don't want to use SSL – just remove the SSL parts from the config and replace port 443 with port 80.</p>

<pre><code class="language-nginx">location ~* .(png|jpe?g|gif|ico|svg)$ {
    expires 24h;
    log_not_found off;
    root '/Users/robin/Sites/robin/public/';

    if (-f $request_filename) {
        break;
    }

    try_files $uri $uri/ @production;
}

location @production {
    resolver 8.8.8.8;
    proxy_pass https://robin.se/$uri;
}
</code></pre>

<p>Don't want to mess with the web server config? Running WordPress? This plugin will do the trick! 
https://wordpress.org/plugins/uploads-by-proxy/</p>

<h2>Bonus</h2>

<p>This works with basically all Nginx configurations, not only Valet – which means you can use it on your Laravel Forge staging server or any other Nginx based web server 🤟</p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
    </feed>
